Guide to the Jane Roberts Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional material, 1975-1981; Accession 1991-M-094
  - Correspondence between Jane Roberts, Robert F. Butts, Jr., publishing personnel, and other individuals concerning the unauthorized distribution and sale of audio tapes of Jane Roberts and Seth speaking in her ESP class, 1975 November-1979 May (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence between Jane Roberts, Robert F. Butts, Jr., and editorial and legal publishing personnel concerning the medical disclaimer in Jane Roberts' The Individual and the Nature of Mass Events: A Seth Book, 1978 December-1981 March (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Additional material, Circa 1977-1986; Accession 1992-M-027
  Gift of Tam Mossman, 1991.
  - Uncorrected proofs, Circa 1977-1986
    - The After Death Journal of an American Philosopher: The World View of William James (Box 1)
    - Dreams, "Evolution," and Value Fulfillment, vol. II (Box 1)
    - The Further Education of Oversoul Seven (Box 1)
    - The God of Jane: A Psychic Manifesto (Box 1)
    - If We Live Again: Or Public Magic and Private Love (Box 1)
    - The Individual and the Nature of Mass Events (A Seth Book) (Box 1)
    - The Nature of the Psyche: Its Human Expression (A Seth Book) (Box 1)
    - The Unknown Reality (A Seth Book), vols. I-II (Box 1)
    - Conversations with Seth: The Story of Jane Roberts ESP Class, Vols. I-II by Susan M. Watkins with an introduction by Jane Roberts (Box 1)
  - Published works
    - Seth Spreekt: De seuwige waarde van de ziel (2 copies), 1979 (Box 2)
  - Tam Mossman material (Box 2)
    - Answers from a Grander Self: Age-Old (and New Age) Questions Asked of a More than Human Personality, edited by Tam Mossman, drafts with some pages missing, Undated (Box 2)
- Additional material, 1975-1991; Accession 1992-M-064
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 1992.
  - Correspondence concerning the use, unauthorized distribution, and sale of audio tapes made of Jane Roberts speaking in her ESP classes both as herself and as her trance personality, Seth, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Dream notebook #8 of Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1990 February 18-1991 December 25 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Additional material, Circa 1940-1981; Accession 1993-M-015
  - Very early poetry (pages 1-122), 1940s-1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Part 1 (pages 1-114A), 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Part 2 (pages 114B-222), 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Poetry (pages 1-111), 1960-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Poetry, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Poetry, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1958-1981 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hi, Low, and Psycho, Circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - The Sky Will Send Down Ladders, Circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Partial books of poetry, Circa 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Poetry to Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1954-1983 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Correspondence between Jane Roberts and editors/publishers, 1952-1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence between Jane Roberts and Blanche Price, 1949-1967 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
- Additional material, 1985-1992; Accession 1993-M-019
  Received from Richard Kendall, 1992.
  - Correspondence to Richard Kendall (previously known as Richard Nissenbaum) from Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1985-1992, undated (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1946-1988; Accession 1993-M-030
  Received from Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1992.
  - Poetry notebook, 1946 April 27-1947 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poetry notebook/notes, 1959-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Poetry notebook/notes, 1979 May-June (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Poetry, 1982 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chronology of Jane Roberts' hospital stays/poetry, 1981 February 15-1982 October (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Practice writing and poetry, 1983 February 9-March (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Psychic predictions, 1983 February 4-April 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Christmas cards by Jane Roberts to Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1966 January-1974 December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Dear Soul" poetry, 1973 November-1979 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Poems (some used in Dreams, "Evolution," and Value Fulfillment ), 1949 February 25-1982 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Poetry (including a song in Sumari, Jane's trance language), 1983 April-1984 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Readers' contributions towards hospitalization costs, 1984 February 17-1988 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 12-15)
- Additional material, 1975-1987; Accession 1993-M-049
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 1993.
  - Contents of the mind, Volumes I-III, material for unpublished book, Circa 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
  - Records of donations for Jane Roberts's hospitalization costs collected by Maude Cardwell (publisher of "Reality Change", the Seth newsletter), 1984 January-1987 August (Box 1, Folder 4-8)
- Additional material, 1980-2002; Accession 1994-M-039
  Received from Seth Network International (Eugene, OR), 1993-1995, 1997-1998. Received from Jobi Harris, 2001.
  Includes subsequent accessions of Reality Change
  - Austin Seth Center Newsletter
    The original title before becoming Reality Change, published by the Austin Seth Center and edited by Maude Cardwell.
    - vol. I: 1-7, 1980 June-December (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - vol. I: 8-12, 1981 January-May (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - vol. II: 1-5, 1981 June-October (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Reality Change: the Newsletter of the Austin Seth Center
    - vol. II: 6-7, 1981 November-December (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - vol. II: 8-12, 1982 January-May (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reality Change: a Newsletter for Readers of the Seth Material
    - vol. III: 1-7, 1982 June-1982 Dec/1983 January (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - vol. III: 8-12, 1983 February-June (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - vol. IV: 1-3, 1983 July-September (Box 1, Folder 5)
      No October, November, December issues published.
    - vol, IV: 4-7, 1984 January-October (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Bimonthly issues; no Jul/Aug, Nov/Dec issues published.
    - vol. V.: 1, 1985 January-February (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Bimonthly issues.
  - Reality Change: a Magazine for People Who Want to Change Their Lives
    - vol. V: 2-4, 1985 July-December (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Bimonthly issues; no Mar/Apr, May/Jun issues published.
    - vol. VI: 1-2, 1986 spring (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - vol. VI: 3, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - vol. VI: 4, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - vol. VII: 1-2, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - vol. VII: 3-4, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - vol. VIII: 1-4, 1991 January-December (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Trimonthly issues.
    - vol. IX: 1-2, 1992 January-June (Box 1, Folder 10)
      No Mar issue published.
    - vol. IX: 3, 1992 winter-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Last issue published by the Austin Seth Center.
  - The SNI Torch: News from Seth Network International, winter 1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    This was the only issue of this newsletter printed.
  - Reality Change: the Global Seth Journal (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Premiere Seth Network International (SNI) issue; published quarterly.
    - 1993 spring, summer, fall 1993 spring, summer, fall (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Winter issue is The SNI Torch.
    - 1994-1997 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 12-15)
    - vol. XII: 1-3, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Last issue of Reality Change published.
  - Seth Store and More, vol. I: 1-2, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Published by SNI; only two issues published.
  - Miscellaneous, 1993-2002 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Printed material pertaining to Seth related conferences and activities.
- Additional material, 1980-1992; Accession 1994-M-041
  - Business and personal correspondence between Jane Roberts, Robert F. Butts, Jr., and Maude Cardwell, pertaining to Cardwell's publication of the quarterly Seth-oriented magazine, Reality Change
    - Vol. I, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Vol. II, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Vol. III, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Vol. IV, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Vol. V, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Vol. VI, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Vol. VII, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional material, 1993-1994; Accession 1994-M-045
  Received from Norman Friedman (Accession 1994-M-045, in folder 1), 1993. Received from Robert F. Butts (Accession 1994-M-046, in folder 2), 1994.
  Includes Accession 1994-M-046.
  - Bridging Science and Spirit: Common Elements on David Bohm's Physics, the Perennial Philosophy and Seth, by Norman Friedman (2 copies), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A Seth Reader, edited by Richard Roberts, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, Circa 1990-1993; Accession 1994-M-055
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 1994, 1996, and 2003.
  Includes Accessions 1996-M-104 and 2003-M-071.
  - Published works in foreign languages
    - Adventures in Consciousness (German, Spanish) (Box 1)
    - Dreams, "Evolution," and Value Fulfillment (Vols. I, II) (Dutch, German) (Box 1)
    - Education of Oversoul 7 (Dutch, German) (Box 1)
    - Emir's Education in the Proper Use of Magical Powers (German) (Box 1)
    - Further education of Oversoul 7 (German) (Box 2)
    - The Individual and the Nature of Mass Events (German) (Box 2)
    - Mass Events (French, Dutch) (Box 2)
    - Nature of the Psyche (German) (Box 2)
    - Oversoul 7 and the Museum of Time (German) (Box 2)
    - Psychic Politics (German) (Box 2)
    - Personal Reality (Danish, Dutch, French, German, Italian) (Box 3)
      - Hungarian editions (Box 3A)
    - Seth Material (Dutch, French, German, Hebrew, Hungarian, Italian, Spanish) (Box 4)
    - Seth Speaks (Dutch, French, German, Hungarian, Italian) (Box 5)
    - Unknown Reality (German) (Box 6)
    - Ling chieh ti hsun hsi: fu t'i ling hun Sai-ssu ti ling I tzu liao (Box 6)
  - Videotapes
    - "The Seth Phenomena: an interview with Robert F. Butts, Jr." [commercially-produced], 1993; videotape (VHS) (Box 7)
    - "Family Photographs of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr.," narrated by Robert F. Butts, Jr., Bob Terrio Productions. [commercially-produced], Undated; videotape (VHS) (Box 8)
      - Use copy, videotape (VHS) (Box 8U)
- Additional material, 1994; Accession 1994-M-092; 0.25; (1 box)
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 1994.
  - The Nature of Personal Reality: Specific, Practical Techniques for Solving Everyday Problems and Enriching the Life You Know, by Jane Roberts; notes and cover art by Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Seth Speaks: the Eternal Validity of the Soul, by Jane Roberts: notes and cover art by Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 1974-1996; Accession 1995-M-118
  Includes Accessions 1996-M-036 and 2000-M-059.
  Received from Robert F. Butts (Accession 1995-M-118), 1995. Received from Richard Kendall (Accessions 1996-M-036 and 2000-M-059), 1995 and 1999.
  - The Magical Approach: Seth Speaks About the Art of Creative Living, by Jane Roberts: notes and cover art by Roberts F. Butts, Jr., 1995 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Accession 1995-M-118.
  - Correspondence to Richard Kendall [previously known as Richard Nissenbaum] from Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1974-1995, undated (Box 1)
    Accession 1996-M-036.
  - Correspondence between Richard Kendall and Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1995-1996 (Box 1)
    Accession 2000-M-059.
- Additional material, 1986; Accession 1996-M-052
  Received from Richard Kendall, 1995.
  - The Seth Video and corresponding audiocassette, 1986 (Box 1)
    This video represents the only visual record of Seth speaking through Jane Roberts and the only filmed interview of Jane Roberts and Robert F. Butts, Jr.
- Additional material, 1970-1979; Accession 1996-M-054
  Received from Seth Network International (Eugene, OR), 1995.
  - The Further Education of Oversoul Seven, by Jane Roberts, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Seth Material, by Jane Roberts, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 1970-1995; Accession 1996-M-069
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 1995-1996.
  Includes Accession 1996-M-104.
  - Books written by Jane Roberts
    - Adventures in Consciousness: An Introduction to Aspect Psychology, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Dialogues of the Soul and Mortal Self in Time, 1975 (Box 1)
    - Dreams, "Evolution," and Value Fulfillment, a Seth Book in two volumes; introductory essays and notes by Robert F. Butts, Jr., 1986 (Box 1)
    - Emir's Education in the Proper Use of Magical Powers, 1979 (Box 1)
    - The Further Education of Oversoul Seven, 1979 (Box 1)
    - The God of Jane: A Psychic Manifesto, 1981 (Box 1)
    - How to Develop Your ESP Power, 1993 ed. (Box 1)
    - If We Live Again: Or, Public Magic and Private Love, 1982 (Box 1)
    - The Individual and the Nature of Mass Events, A Seth Book, 1981, 1995 (Box 2)
    - The Nature of the Psyche: Its Human Expression, A Seth Book, 1979 (Box 2)
    - Oversoul Seven and the Museum of Time, 1984 (Box 2)
    - The Oversoul Trilogy, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Psychic Politics: An Aspect Psychology Book, 1976 (Box 2)
    - The Seth Material, 1970, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Seth Speaks: The Eternal Validity of the Soul, 1972 (Box 2)
    - The Unknown Reality, volume I of the Seth Book, 1977 (Box 2)
    - Stopford-Strausz-Hupé, 1977 (Box 2)
- Additional material, Circa 1930-1955; Accession 1996-M-094
  Received from Robert F. Butts, 1996.
  - Photographs of Jane Roberts as a child and an adult, some include family members, Circa 1930-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Additional material, 1994-2018; Accession 1997-M-039
  Received from Madelon Rose Logue, 1996-ongoing.
  Accruals
  New issues of Black Sheep typically received quarterly.
  - The Collected Poems of Black Sheep, 1994-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Index to Black Sheep (covering issues 1-104), by Sue R. Williams, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Black Sheep
    A Seth/Jane Roberts funzine, edited by Madelon Rose Logue.
    - Issues 1-79, 1994-2007 November (Box 1, Folder 2-13)
    - Issues 80-104, 2007 December-2012 January (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
    - Issues 105-121, 2012 February-2014 November (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - Index to Black Sheep (covering issues 1-110), by Sue R. Williams, 2013 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Issues 122-144, 2015-01-2018-09 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Index to Black Sheep (covering issues 1-134),by Sue R. Williams, 2017 January (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Additional material, 1972-1996; Accession 1998-M-074
  Gift of Tam Mossman, 1997 and 2001.
  Includes Accession 2001-M-064.
  - Correspondence of Tam Mossman with Robert F. Butts, Jr. and Richard Bach, 1972, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Correspondence with Robert F. Butts, Jr. includes Accession 2001-M-064.
  - Conversations with Seth: the Story of Jane Roberts's ESP Class, by Susan M. Watkins, with an introduction by Jane Roberts, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Seth: Dreams and Projection of Consciousness, by Jane Roberts, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional material, 1967-1989; Accession 1998-M-079
  Also includes Accession 1998-M-125. The audiocassettes of Jane Roberts' ESP class sessions in this accession were made by Richard Kendall, possibly from the reel-to-reel tapes recorded by Don Hall that are in Accession 2002-M-015. Compact discs (and use copies) in Accession 2001-M-058 may duplicate the contents of the audiocassettes in this accession.
  Received from Richard Kendall, 1997.
  - "ESP Class Notes," by Richard Kendall, 1967-1978 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Dreaming Myself, Dreaming A Town, by Susan M. Watkins, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Watkins was a participant in Jane Roberts's ESP classes.
  - Index and notes from donor for audiocassettes of Jane Roberts' ESP classes (boxes 2-24), Circa 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Audio cassette tapes (Nos.1-23) of Jane Roberts' ESP classes, 1972 September 26-1973 May 22
    See also: Accession 2001-M-058, box 1
    - 1972 September 26, Tape 1; 1 (Box 2)
    - 1972 October 3, Tape 2; 1 (Box 3)
    - 1972 October 10, Tape 3; 1 (Box 4)
    - 1972 October 17, Tape 4; 1 (Box 5)
    - 1972 October 31, November 7, Tape 5; 1 (Box 6)
    - 1972 November 14, 21, 28, December 5, Tape 6; 1 (Box 7)
    - 1972 December 5, 12, Tape 7; 1 (Box 8)
    - 1972 December 19, Tape 8; 1 (Box 9)
    - 1973 January 9, Tape 9; 1 (Box 10)
    - 1973 January 23, Tape 10; 1 (Box 11)
    - 1973 January 30, Tape 11; 1 (Box 12)
    - 1973 February 6, Tape 12; 1 (Box 13)
    - 1973 February 13, 20, 27, Tape 13; 1 (Box 14)
    - 1973 March 13, Tape 14; 1 (Box 15)
    - 1973 March 20, Tape 15; 1 (Box 16)
    - 1973 March 27, Tape 16; 1 (Box 17)
    - 1973 April 3, 10, Tape 17; 1 (Box 18)
    - 1973 April 17, Tape 18; 1 (Box 19)
    - 1973 April 24, Tape 19; 1 (Box 20)
    - 1973 May 1, Tape 20; 1 (Box 21)
    - 1973 May 8, Tape 21; 1 (Box 22)
    - 1973 May 15, Tape 22; 1 (Box 23)
    - 1973 May 22, Tape 23; 1 (Box 24)
  - Lawrence Davidson's telephone interview of Jane Roberts; also includes Algis J. Budrys' comments on meeting with Jane Roberts, 1977; 1 (Box 25)
    This item constitutes Accession 1998-M-125.
- Additional material, 1997; Accession 1999-M-055
  Received from Seth Network International (Eugene, OR), 1998.
  - Adventures in Consciousness: An Introduction to Aspect Psychology, by Jane Roberts, published volume and accompanying audiobook containing two cassettes, 1997 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1999; Accession 2000-M-060
  Received from Ron Heckens (Accession 2000-M-060, in folder 1), 1999. Received from Anita Newell and Nancy Walker (Accession 2000-M-093, in folder 2), 2000.
  Includes Accession 2000-M-093.
  - "Ouija Board Session," video tape and duplicate taken for Robert F. Butts, Jr.'s eightieth birthday, 1999 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Ouija Board Session," typed transcript, 1999 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 2000-2001; Accession 2000-M-094
  Received from Mary Rouen (Brass Ring Bookstore), 2000-2001.
  Includes Accessions 2000-M-116, 2001-M-027, 2001-M-059, and 2001-M-073.
  - Perspectives, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
    Newsletter published by the Brass Ring Bookstore.
- Additional material, 1984-1988; Accession 2000-M-099
  Received from Madelon Rose Logue, 2000.
  - Publications containing articles pertaining to Jane Roberts, Seth, and related topics
    - Cypress: The Psychic Digest, vol. 1, 1988 (Box 1)
    - New Age: Gainsville, issues 3 and 4, 1984 Jan, May (Box 1)
    - Sumari Sights: Newsletter for the Greater D.C. Seth Society, vol. 1, numbers 1-3, [4?], 1984; vol 2, number 4, 1985 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1999-2001; Accession 2001-M-049
  Received from Moment Point Press, 2001.
  Researchers wishing to use the fan mail in Accessions 1985-M-014, 2002-M-027, and 2003-M-029 must sign an "Access agreement for the fan mail in the Jane Roberts Papers" in order to be given access to this material.
  - Conversations with Seth: the Story of Jane Roberts's ESP Class, by Susan Watkins, revised, volumes I and II combined, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    See also various drafts of this publication in Accession 2001-M-063.
    See: Accession 2001-M-049, box 1, folder 1
  - Speaking of Jane Roberts: Remembering the Author of the Seth Material, by Susan Watkins, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 1988-2002; Accession 2001-M-054
  Received from Rick Stack (New Awareness Network), 2001-2002.
  Includes Accessions 2002-M-024 and 2003-M-019.
  - The Early Sessions, by Jane Roberts
    - Books 1-8 of the Seth material, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
      Includes sessions 1-421, which took place 1963 Nov-1968 Jul 8.
    - Book 9 of the Seth material, 2002 (Box 1A, Folder 5)
      Includes sessions 422-510, which took place 1968 Jul 10-1970 Jan 19.
  - Out-of-Body Adventures: 30 Days to the Most Exciting Experience of Your Life, by Rick Stack, 1988 (Box 1A, Folder 6)
    Stack was a student of Jane Roberts.
  - The Seth Audio Collection, produced by New Awareness Network, 1990
    Recordings of Seth speaking through Jane Roberts.
    - Tapes 1-6 (Box 2)
      Includes transcripts.
    - Tapes 7-17 (Box 3)
- Additional material, 1956-1982; Accession 2001-M-056
  Received from Mary Dillman (Accessions 2001-M-056 and 2002-M-006), 2001. Received from Barry Noonan (Accessions 2002-M-005 and 2005-M-012), 2001 and 2004.
  Includes Accessions 2002-M-005, 2002-M-006, and 2005-M-012. Comprises science fiction and fantasy stories written by Jane Roberts and published in magazines and anthologies, as well as a short novel. Materials are arranged chronologically by the publication date of the selection in which they appear.
  - Magazines
    - Dude
      This item is Accession 2005-M-012.
      - "The Big Freeze", 1965 November (Box 1)
    - Fantastic Universe
      This item is Accession 2002-M-005.
      - "First Communion", 1957 March (Box 1)
    - The Magazine of Fantasy and Science Fiction (Box 1)
      - "The Red Wagon", 1956 December (Box 1)
      - "The Canvas Pyramid", 1957 March (Box 1)
      - "The Chestnut Beads", 1957 October (Box 1)
      - "The Bundu", 1958 March (Box 1)
      - "A Demon at Devotions", 1958 September (Box 1)
      - "Nightmare", 1959 April (Box 1)
      - "Impasse", 1959 July (Box 1)
      - "Three Times Around", 1964 May (Box 1)
  - The Rebellers, a novella, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Anthologies (Box 1)
    - Rod Serling's Triple W: Witches, Warlocks, and Werewolves (Box 1)
      - "The Chestnut Beads", 1963 (Box 1)
    - Ladies of Fantasy: Two Centuries of Sinister Stories by the Gentle Sex (Box 2)
      - "The Red Wagon", 1975 (Box 2)
    - Earth Invaded
      - "Three Times Around", 1982 (Box 2)
- Additional material, 1972-1974; Accession 2001-M-058
  Received from Mary Dillman, Richard Kendall, Mary Rouen, and Sue Watkins, 2000.
  This accession comprises compact discs of recordings made of Jane Roberts' ESP class sessions by Don Hall. According to one of the donors, CD#1-CD#23 were made from Richard Kendall's audiocassette recordings in Accession 1998-M-079, which were made from Hall's reel-to-reel tapes. The remaining compact discs in this accession were made directly from Hall's reel-to-reel tapes, which are in Accession 2002-M-015. See also compact discs in Accession 2004-M-087, which fill in dates missing in this accession.
  - Jane Roberts' ESP class sessions
    - 1972 September 26, CD #1; 1 (Box 1)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 1U)
    - 1972 October 3, CD #2; 1 (Box 2)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 2U)
    - 1972 October 10, CD #3; 1 (Box 3)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 3U)
    - 1972 October 17, CD #4; 1 (Box 4)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 4U)
    - 1972 October 31, November 7, CD #5; 1 (Box 5)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 5U)
    - 1972 November 14, 21, 28, December 5, CD #6; 1 (Box 6)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 6U)
    - 1972 December 5, 12, CD #7; 1 (Box 7)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 7U)
    - 1972 December 19, CD #8; 1 (Box 8)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 8U)
    - 1973 January 9, CD #9; 1 (Box 9)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 9U)
    - 1973 January 23, CD #10; 1 (Box 10)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 10U)
    - 1973 January 30, CD #11; 1 (Box 11)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 11U)
    - 1973 February 6, CD #12; 1 (Box 12)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 12U)
    - 1973 February 13, 20, 27, CD #13; 1 (Box 13)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 13U)
    - 1973 March 13, CD #14; 1 (Box 14)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 14U)
    - 1973 March 20, CD #15; 1 (Box 15)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 15U)
    - 1973 March 27, CD #16; 1 (Box 16)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 16U)
    - 1973 April 3, 10, CD #17; 1 (Box 17)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 17U)
    - 1973 April 17, CD #18; 1 (Box 18)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 18U)
    - 1973 April 24, CD #19; 1 (Box 19)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 19U)
    - 1973 May 1, CD #20; 1 (Box 20)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 20U)
    - 1973 May 8, CD #21; 1 (Box 21)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 21U)
    - 1973 May 15, CD #22; 1 (Box 22)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 22U)
    - 1973 May 22, CD #23; 1 (Box 23)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 23U)
    - 1973 June 5, 19, CD #24A; 1 (Box 24)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 24U)
    - 1973 June 19, 26, CD #24B; 1 (Box 25)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 25U)
    - 1973 August 7, CD #25A; 1 (Box 26)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 26U)
    - 1973 August 14, CD #25B; 1 (Box 27)
      - Use copy, 1 (Box 27U)